Adams family papers
Litchfield Historical Society
- Correspondence
  - Wheelock, Mary Adams (1838-1895)
    - Wheelock, Mary Adams, 1870-1872 (Folder 5)
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles, 1870 Jan 31 (Folder 5)
        Wheelock writes about news of family and friends, including dining with Charley Graves last night.
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles, 1870 Feb 6 (Folder 5)
        Wheelock writes about her concern for her father's health and news of family.
      - Wheelock, John to Adams, Charles, 1870 Feb 6 (Folder 5)
        John Wheelock's letter was sent with Mary's 1870 Feb 6 letter. He discusses arrangements relating to Ella, Mary, and Fannie.
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles, 1870 May 27 (Folder 5)
        Wheelock writes about the funeral services for Joseph and that her thoughts are with her father very much.
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles, 1871 Mar 11 (Folder 5)
        Wheelock writes about her concern for Fannie and news of family and friends. It is very kind of him to invite her home for the summer, but she cannot leave her husband and duties here.
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles, 1872 Apr 17 (Folder 5)
        Wheelock writes that she feels half sick and good for nothing. She wishes she could spirit herself to Litchfield during the day because the hours are long and she feels lonely until John comes home. She describes their journey to New York.
    - Greene, Marie Barton to Wheelock, Mary Adams, 1864 (Folder 6)
      Marie Barton Greene worked with the Christian Commission and Sanitary Commission attending to wounded Civil War soldiers as they arrived in Washington, D.C. She sent two letters to a sister of Charles Adams (1845-1864), Mary Adams Wheelock, describing how she attended Adams during the last hours of his life on June 11, 1864. Adams had been been severely wounded in the Civil War Battle of Cold Harbor. John H. Hubbard and several others were present. One letter includes a poem she wrote "suggested by meeting and watching beside" Charles "in his last moments."
- Other papers
  - Adams, Joseph (1767-1856) last will and testament, 1841 (Folder 1)
  - Adams, Joseph (1767-1856) last will and testament, circa 1850 (Folder 2)
  - Adams, Julia Hinman (1810-1869), "What Aunt Julia said..." (Folder 3)
    Document recording the last words of Julia Hinman Adams.
  - Baldwin, Daniel estate distribution, 1840 (Folder 4)
  - Brewer, Jehoida, "Hiding Place", circa early 1800s (Folder 5)
    Handwritten copy of Brewer's 1776 poem.
  - Bulkley, David C., St. Paul's Lodge No. Eleven lease, 1860 Jul 26 (Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1886, 1928 (Folder 7)
    Amos Adams Lawrence obituary, 1886 Aug 22, and Charles Hinman Graves obituary, 1928 Oct.
  - Head Quarters Military District, Washington, D.C., pass for Charles Adams, 1863 Aug 13 (Folder 8)
  - Herbert, Morris citizenship record, 1863 (Folder 9)
  - Holt, Kezia Adams (1747-1811) last will and testament (Folder 10)
  - Knitting instructions, circa 1850s (Folder 11)
  - Phoenix Bank receipts, 1814, 1822 (Folder 12)
  - Waugh, Lucy B., lines suggested on attending the funeral of the late Charles Adams, 1864 Jun 26 (Folder 13)
  - Wedding cards, 1860s (Folder 14)
    Clara C. Vaill, Mr. & Mrs. Charles E. Robinson, Miss Amelia H. Buck, Dr. & Mrs. Alfred North.
  - Wheelock, Mary Adams, transcription of David Gray's poem "Outrivalled", circa 1860s (Folder 15)
  - Litchfield Enquirer, The, 1864 Jun 18
    Entire third and fourth page. Contains extensive coverage of the Civil War Battle of Cold Harbor, a list of killed and wounded, and obituaries of Luman Wadhams, Charles Adams (1845-1864), and Lyman Smith. Currently housed in 18B oversize box 17.
  - Marsh, Solomon estate survey, 1857 Jun 29
    Currently housed in 18B oversize box 9.
- Photographs
  - Unidentified male silhouette, undated (Folder 1)
  - Album, 1860s-1870s
    Album of 36 cartes de viste, most unidentified. Cover has "Julia M. Adams Dec. 7th 1862." stamped on it. Currently housed in 3A Box 4.
- Albums
  - Adams, Jane Hinman (1806-1828), 1825-1827
    Album of poems inscribed to Jane C. Hinman. "J. C. Hinman" is stamped on the cover. Later annotated. Her husband, Charles Adams, recorded her death and a poem on July 30, 1828. Currently housed in 3A box 4.
  - Adams, Julia Hinman (1810-1869), 1827-1830, 1850
    Album of handwritten poems. "Miss Julia M. Hinman" written on endpaper. Later annotated. Currently housed in 3A box 4.
  - Adams, Jane Hinman (1806-1828) and Adams, Julia Hinman (1810-1869), circa 1827, 1848-1853
    Album of poems probably copied by Jane C. Adams. "J.M.H." written on front endpaper. Diary entries from 1848-1853 added by Julia Hinman Adams. Currently housed in 3A box 5.